Good evening ladies and gentlemen. A
very warm welcome to ICIC Lumbard
General Insurance Company Limited Q4 and
FI 2025 earnings conference call. From
the senior management we have with us
today Mr. Sanjiv Mantri MD and CEO of
the company Mr. Gopal Balchandran CFO
Mr. Girish Nyak Chief Technology and
Health Underwriting and Claims Mr. Sep
Kurada Chief Corporate Solutions
International Bank assurance Mr. Alan
Singhi, chief retail and government
business. Mr. Korov Aurora, chief
reinsurance underwriting and claims for
property and casualty. Please note that
any statements comments are made in
today's call that may look like
forward-looking statements are based on
information presently available to the
management and do not constitute any
indication of any future performance as
future involves risk and uncertainties
which could cause results to differ
materially from the current views being
expressed. As a reminder, all
participant lines will be in the
listenon mode and there will be an
opportunity for you to ask questions
after the presentation concludes. Should
you need assistance during the
conference call, please signal an
operator by pressing star then zero on
your touch on phone. I now hand the
conference over to Mr. Sanjiv Mantri, MD
and CEO ICIC Lumbard General Insurance
Limited. Thank you and over to you.
Good evening to each one of you. Thank
you for joining the earning conference
call at ICL Lombard General Insurance
Company Limited for quarter 4 and
financial year 2025.
Let me give you a brief overview of the
trends we observed in the economy as
well as the industry followed by an
overview of the business. Post this our
CFO Mr. Gopal Walachandran will share
the financial performance of the company
for the quarter and the year ended 31st
March
2025. The the GDP growth for the quarter
ended December 2024 stood at 6.2% versus
5.6% 6% for the quarter ended September
2024. As per the data released by Moxy,
high frequency indicators like eway
bills, toll collections, diesel
consumption and GST collections during
quarter 4 of financial year 2025 are all
indicating positive economic conditions.
Further, MOPS has revised the fullear
GDP estimates to 6.5% on Feb 28, 2025
versus 6.4% 4% published on Jan 7,
2025. Let me not dwell on certain
industry trends which can have an impact
on the general insurance industry at
large. As indicated during the last
quarter, the government expenditure
remained flat which impacted the
commercial line segment growth for the
current quarter. However, we have
started seeing an uptick in government
spending towards capital expenditure in
past few months. This may be a positive
for the commercial line of business.
For the auto industry, we had seen a
growth in rural market in Q3 of 2025.
Specifically for two viller segment at
12.7% and the tractor segment at
20.1%. As reported by FAR. However, in
quarter 4, 2025, we have seen a degrowth
of 1.9% for the two-heer segment and a
degrowth of 4.6% for the tractor
segment. This indicates a softer rural
demand.
The private car segment grew by 1.1% and
the commercial vement vehicle segment
had a degrowth of 3.8% for quarter 4
financial year
2025 as reported by far which had an
impact on motor insurance growth for
quarter 4 financial year 2025. However,
for the coming year the auto industry is
expected to have mid singledigit growth.
We remain positive for the motor
insurance business with increasing
penetration in the old vehicle
segments. The health segment continues
to be one of the fastest growing
segments and is the largest contributor
to the industry constituting 38.1% of
the GDP mix for financial year 2025.
However, the industry growth in
financial year 2025 was impacted due to
the one by accounting norm and lower
growth in the health segment, health
benefit segment attributable to lower
dispersement by of credit by NBFC's and
MFIs. We believe that the increasing
demand for health protection coupled
with increased medical inflation may
drive double-digit growth in the health
segment in the coming year. Here were
some key economic changes which were
announced during quarter 4 financial
year
2025. The budgetary announcement of
income tax relief provided is expected
to result in an additional 1 trillion in
the hands of Indian taxpaying population
thereby leading to a high disposable
income. The second consecutive interest
rate cut tweaking of norms applicable to
NBFC lending coupled with infusion of
liquidity by RBI should also support
credit growth.
These policy changes aim to encourage
spending and investment. They are also
expected to stimulate demand for goods
and services thereby boosting
consumption and preparing demand for
risk protection through insurance
solutions. However, we remain vigilant
on the ongoing geopolitical developments
which may pose risk to both global
growth and the Indian
economy. Now, let me give you a brief
give you an update on the regulatory
developments. The regulatory the
authority during financial year 2025
continued with various reforms seeking
to expand the market and increase the
penetration of insurance product towards
the mission of insurance for all by
2047.
I would like to mention key circulars
which were introduced in quarter 4 2025
regarding capping the increase in senior
citizens health insurance premium rates
to 10% peranom and introduction of BIMA
ESBA facility for health insurance
policies. We believe these regulatory
changes will improve affordability and
create operational ease for policy
holders. Overall, we remain positive
that the GI industry is poised to grow
in the medium to long term given the
favorable economic and regulatory
environment, low penetration and
relatively higher disposable
income. Now coming to the industry
performance for quarter 4 and financial
year
2025. The gross direct premium income
grew by 1.7% and 6.2% for quarter 4 2025
and financial year 2025 respectively.
Excluding the impact of the 1 byN
accounting norm, the GDPI grew by 8.6%
for financial year
2025. Excluding crop and mass health,
the GDPI grew by 4.9% and 8% for quarter
4 2025 and financial year 2025
respectively. Speaking on the specific
segments within the industry, the
commercial segment reported a marginal
degrowth of 1.2% 2% and growth of 1.5%
for quarter 4 and financial year 2025.
Within this, the fire segment registered
a degrowth of 1.8% and 5.3% for quarter
4 financial year 2025 and financial year
2025 respectively on account of pricing
pressure excluding the fire segment. The
over overall commercial segment grew by
8 and a half% for financial year 2025.
The motor segment grew by 6.9% for
quarter 4 of financial year 2025 and 8%
for financial year 2025. The growth in
the segment has been lower due to muted
vehicle sales and continued pricing
pressures reflected by high industry
combined
ratio. The health se the health segment
grew at 3.7% and 9% for quarter 4 2025
and financial year 2025. Within this
group health grew at 4.5% and 10.6% for
quarter 4 2025 and financial year 2025
respectively and retail health grew at
7.6% and 12.1% in quarter 4 2025 and
financial year 2025 respectively.
Looking at the underlying performance of
the industry, you may recall our
discussion a year back during our
earnings call where we expect we where
we expected some semblance in
underwriting discipline in the market
due to improvement in the industry's
combined ratio during that period.
However, the combined ratio for the
industry has actually worsened to
113.2% for 9 month as against 112.2% 2%
for 9 month financial year 2024. The
combined ratio for the private sector
has worsened to triple 1.21% for 9 month
2025 from 108.3% for 9 month financial
year 2024. The industry worsening was
largely due to motor segment combined
ratio which increased to
123.8% in 9 month financial year 2025 as
against
118.2% in 9 month financial year 2024.
Our continued focus on driving
profitable growth helped us to improve
our combined ratio from
103.7% in 9 month financial year 2024 to
102.8% in 9 months financial year 2025
and
103.3% in full financial year 2024 to
102.6% in financial for the financial
year 2025 on N
basis. I will now walk you through the
company performance across key business
segments during quarter 4 and financial
year 2025.
The company's GDPR registered a growth
of 8% for quarter 4 2025 and 11% for
financial year 2025 on N basis with the
1 byN accounting norm for quarter 4 2025
the company registered a growth of 2.3%
is as against the industry growth of
1.7% and for financial year 2025 the
company registered a growth of 8.3% as
against the industry growth of 6.2% 2%
excluding crop and mass health. The
company's growth was 2.2% and
7.7% compared to the industry growth of
4.9% and 8% for quarter 4 2025 and
financial year 2025
respectively. In the commercial line
segment in quarter 4 2025 our growth was
at 2.8% is against the industry growth
of 1.2%.
For financial year 2025, we grew by 2.5
2.1% as against the industry growth of 1
and a half%. Thereby maintaining market
share. This indicates the strength of a
brand relationship and service quality
in an environment where industry face
continued pricing pressure throughout
the year. In the fire segment, we grew
in line with the industry and in marine
cargo engineering and liability lines of
business. We reported growth higher than
the industry leading to market share
accretion.
In motor segment we grew at.1% for
quarter 4 2025 as against the industry
growth of
6.9%. We continue to drive our motor
strategy based on granular portfolio
segmentation and food and risk
selection. For the financial year 2025
we grew by 11 and a half% as again the
industry growth of 8%. Consequently our
market share grew to 10.8% 8% for
financial year 2025 versus 10.5% for
financial year 2024. The portfolio mix
for private car, two wheeler and CV
stood at
53.4%,
25.4% and 21.2% respectively. Our
continued focus on multi- channelannel
distribution, underwriting capabilities
and efficient claim settlement and
actual practices helped us in
maintaining a leadership position.
Moving to the health segment, we grew by
22.1% and 19.2% for quarter 4 financial
year 2025 and financial year 2025
respectively. With the one by hand
accounting lod by 9.7% and 12.6% for
quarter 4 2025 and financial year 2025
respectively. Our retail health segment
registered a growth at 47.7% for quarter
4 financial year 2025 with the 1 byN
accounting norm. The growth of quarter 4
2025 was 25.1% as against the industry
growth of 7.6%.
For financial year 2025, the overall
growth stood at
38.1%. With one by an accounting norm,
the growth for financial year 2025 was
25% as again the industry growth of
12.1%. As a result, we gained market
share from 3% in financial year 2024 to
3.3% for financial year 2025.
The group health employs employee
segment witnessed growth of 24.9% and
18.5% for quarter 4 2025 and financial
year
2025 respectively. A group other
business
deg the degrowth was 30% for quarter 4
2025. For financial year 2025, group
other business had a muted growth of
5.3% on account of impact on health
benefit business through the banker
channel with the one by accounting
norms. This segment showed a degrowth of
10.5% for the
year. We had spoken about various one
team initiatives in earlier earnings
call. One of the initiatives we had
spoken about was the consolidation of
customerf facing digital assets like I
take care help apps and digital
alliances under one digital to deliver a
superior customer experience and to
drive efficiencies. Some of the digital
outcomes achieved in financial year 2025
include increasing unique customer visit
by 2x on our digital platform. 37%
growth in fresh transactions on our
digital platform. Downloads for our
one-stop solution one take your app
surpassed surpassed 14.9
million. The business done through the
app stood at 9 927.7 million and 2653.2
2 million for quarter 4, financial year
2025 and financial year 2025
respectively. Consequently, our
customerf facing digital asset business
grew by
15.8% constituting 6.6% of our overall
GDP for financial year 2025.
Now I would like to share with you some
initiatives taken by us for improving
the customer experience and driving
efficiencies for
claims. On the motor side, a preferred
partner network serviced up
74.1% of our nonm claims in quarter 4
2025 up from 69.6% in quarter 4 2024.
For financial year 2025, this number
stood at 73.2%. 2% up from 65% in
financial year
2024. Our cloud calling facilities were
used by 89.6% of our motor customers in
quarter 4 financial year 2025 as against
77% in quarter 4 2024. For the full year
this number was at 86% as against 49%
previous year. This resulted in the
reduction of cost to claim ratio by 21%
for the
year.
Our average claim settlement period for
retail lines of business has seen
improvement from 6 days in financial
year 2024 to 5 days in financial year
2025 for motor and for motor and for
five and from 5 days in financial year
2024 to 3 days in financial year 2025
for health. Our ISI initiative which was
launched in April 2024 offered an
onground claim support to over 90,000
customers across 56 cities and 2,500
hospital network in financial year
2025. A focus on customer experience and
process efficiencies has led to healthy
NPS of 67 and 69 for health and motor
claims respectively for 9 months
2025. With all the above efforts, we are
pleased to share that the company's
premium growth has been higher by 210
basis points as against the industry
growth. Our focus on driving profitable
opportunities has further resulted in
improvement in the combined ratio from
103.3% in financial year 2024 to 102.6%
in financial year 2025 on N basis. on on
the 1 byN accounting norm the combined
ratio stood at
102.8% leading to a pad growth of
30.7% and then delivering ROE for the
year at 19.1%.
As we enter into the new financial year,
we remain committed to achieving the
desired scale through creation of
positive customer experiences,
leveraging data analytics and a
technology first approach, harnessing a
multi-product multi-distribution
strategy and with a continued focus on
product
innovation with a core philosophy of one
team, we continue to scale up the profit
pools and to drive sustainable growth.
I will now request Gopal to take you
through the financial numbers for the
recently concluded quarter and financial
year. Thanks Ajivie and uh good evening
to each one of you. I will now give you
a brief overview of the financial
performance for the recently concluded
quarter and the financial year. We have
uploaded the results presentation on our
website. You can access it as we walk
you through the performance numbers.
With effect from October 1, 2024,
long-term products are accounted on a 1
byN basis as mandated by the regulator.
Hence, Q4 and FI25 numbers are not
comparable with prior periods. For more
details on the impact, refer to slide
number 15 of our investor presentation
for further details. The gross direct
premium income of the company was at
rupes 268.33 billion in FI25 as against
rupees 247.76 billion in FI24. a growth
of 8.3% as against industry growth of
6.2%. GDP of the company was at 62.11
billion in Q4 FI25 as against 60.73
billion in Q4 FI24. A growth of 2.3% as
against industry growth of
1.7%. On the retail side of the
business, GDP of the motor segment was
at 107.4 billion in FI25 as against
96.34 billion in FI24, registering a
growth of 11.5%.
The advanced premium for the motor
segment was at rupes 37.17 billion at
March 31 2025 as against 36.44 billion
as at December 31 2024. GDP of the L
segment was at rupes 69.5 billion in
FI25 as against 61.71 billion in FI24
registering a growth of 12.6%. Our
agents which includes the point of sale
distribution count was at 1 lak 40,736
as at March 31 2025 up from 1 lakh 40,77
as at December 31 2024. GDP of our
commercial line segment was at 69.95
billion in FI25 as against 68.51 billion
in FI24 registering a growth of 2.1% as
against industry growth of
1.5%. Resultedly our combined ratio
stood at 102.8%. 8% for FI25 as against
103.3% for FI24 excluding the impact of
CAT losses of 94 billion in FI25 and
1.37 billion in FI24. The combined ratio
was 102.4% and 102.5% respectively.
Combined ratio for quarter 4 FI25 was
102.5% as against 102.3% in quarter 4
FI24. Our investment assets during the
quarter rose to rupes 535.0 08 billion
as at March 31, 2025, up from rupees
515.99 97 billion as at December 31,
2024. Our investment leverage net of
borrowing was 3.74 times as at March 31,
2025 as against 3.76 times at December
31, 2024. Investment income was at 42.5
billion in FI25 as against 36.1 billion
in FI24. On a quarterly basis,
investment income was at 8.77 billion in
Q4 FI25 as against 9.54 billion in Q4
FI24. Our capital gains net of
impairment on investment assets stood at
rupees 8.02 billion for the full year as
compared to 5.51 billion in the previous
financial year. Capital gains net of
impairment on investment assets stood at
rupees.06 06 billion in quarter 4 FI25
as compared to rups 1.56 billion in
quarter 4
fi24. Our profit before tax grew by 30%
at 33.21 billion in FI25 as against
25.55 billion in FI24. Whereas PBT grew
by 4.2% at 6.68 billion in quarter 4
FI25 as against 6.98 billion rupees in
quarter 4 FI24.
Consequently, profit after tax grew by
30.7% at 25.08 billion in FI25 as
against 19.19 billion in FI24. PAD
regrrew by 1.9% to rupees 5.1 billion in
Q4 FI25 as against 5.19 billion in
quarter 4 FI24. The board of directors
of the company has proposed a final
dividend of rupees 7 per share for FI25.
This statement is however subject to
approval of shareholders in the ensuing
annual general meeting of the company.
The overall dividend for FI25 including
the proposed final dividend is rupees
12.5 per share. Last year the overall
dividend was rupees 11 per share. Return
on average equity was 19.1% in FI25 as
against 17.2% in FI24. Return on equity
for quarter 4 this year was 14.5 as
against 17.8 in quarter 4 of last year.
Solveny ratio was at 2.69 times at March
31 2025 as against 2.36 times at
December 31, 2024 continued to be higher
than the regulatory minimum requirement
of 1.5. As I conclude, I would like to
assert that we remain focused on our
strategy of driving profitable growth,
consistent and sustainable value
creation for all our stakeholders while
ensuring that the interest of policy
holders is in the forefront at all
times. I'd like to thank you all for
attending this earnings call and we will
be happy to take any questions that you
may have. Thank you.
Thank you. We will now begin the
question and answer session. Anyone who
wishes to ask a question may press star
and one on your touchstone telephone. If
you wish to remove yourself from the
question queue, you may press star and
two. Participants are requested to use
handsets while asking a question. Ladies
and gentlemen will wait for a moment
while the question queue
assembles. The first question comes on
the line of Pra Jane from Mutal Oswal
Financial Services Limited. Please go
ahead.
Yeah. Hi. Uh a good set of numbers on
especially on the combined ratio front.
Uh just your thoughts on uh know how do
we see the growth from here. uh firstly
no from a overall GWP perspective uh
given the one by impact would continue
uh to be there in one match of mix one
of FI26 and second half would see
unwinding of uh the GWP uh and
contributing to some part of growth. So
that would be uh the first question. Uh
second question would be on your
combined ratio or whether you would look
at combined ratio or further improving
from the one that reported uh in in the
for
FI25
and on the fire segment if you could
highlight you know what are the kind of
renewals we've seen in January and uh
also in the uh in the April renewals
those questions thanks
Okay. Yeah. Thanks PR. I think uh with
respect to the growth uh even when I was
reading in terms of uh what it is line
by line I had covered but again I'll
I'll talk about it uh motor per se we
are expecting on the new sale mid single
digit. We also going by the numbers as
has been put across by other OEMs as to
what they are seeing. Albeit the base on
the private car in particular is high.
Uh I also spoke about the fact that the
quarter 4 two-heer numbers were they're
negative which was a bit of a surprise
as what we saw in quarter three and
commercial vehicle I would be more
positive overall because government
capex and lot of other activities which
in the last financial year had remained
subdued should get picked up. So net net
motor we will see single digit to maybe
at just about double digit growth is
what our prediction is and look all of
these things can change real time we'll
keep you updated but that's what our
belief is on the health side pre our own
belief is we will should see double
digit growth uh now health is two
components retail health and as well as
the group health part of it I'm more
clearly talking about the retail health
path which will continue to see far more
uh incremental business in terms of new
to insurance and also there would be
whatever interest growth that comes out
in terms of overall this. So we would
remain positive on help and help with a
38% contribution will not be surprised
if we see that contribution probably
going to a 40% and thereabouts and
becomes the largest and will continue to
be the largest player. The last but uh
not the least in terms of the commercial
line of business uh we've had a very one
of the most difficult years on
commercial line if you see uh you've
never seen a growth of this nature going
to you know single digit in last 7 to
eight
years clearly it had multiple factors
fire pricing which we spoke about it
however going forward as V.